[Music]
in a section of the british medical
journal called minerva where they
compile interesting little snippets
they published a picture of a woman who
they found had taped a cabbage leaf to
her knee
she said that this was the only measure
that provided relief from the symptoms
of her osteoarthritis
some doctors responded with bemusement
others were like duh amazed to see the
photograph not because a cabbage leaf
was used but that this was considered
newsworthy the doctor disclosed she may
be a little biased though as she admits
of being a cabbage leaf user herself
there's nothing new about this ancient
remedy wrote another reader used to help
reduce all kinds of painful swelling
freshly washed cabbage leaves are known
in european folk medicine as the poor
man's poultice so there's nothing
freakish or stupid about putting cabbage
leaves on your knees
okay i didn't realize it was such a
touchy topic
of course we'll never really know if it
actually works i mean it's never been a
randomized controlled trial of topical
cabbage leaves for osteoarthritis and
there never will be
until
now
the efficacy of cabbage leaf wraps and
the treatment of symptomatic
osteoarthritis of the knee a randomized
controlled trial
wait
how did this study even get funded
a family foundation just stepped forward
and paid for it i love that
in fact the former president and first
lady of germany's foundation after all
osteoarthritis of the knee is one of the
most common
chronic diseases among older adults so
let's test the effects of cabbage leaf
wraps why not
patients with confirmed osteoarthritis
in the knees were randomly assigned to
four weeks of treatment with a cabbage
leaf on their knees every day
or a topical pain gel containing an
anti-inflammatory drug
or neither
even better would have been a fourth
group applying like iceberg lettuce
leaves but i'll take what i can get
here's a graph of pain intensity over
the 28-day experiment here's how the
drug worked
not much better than doing nothing
but the cabbage worked better
overall the study found that a four-week
application of cabbage leaves was more
effective than usual care with respect
to pain
functional disability and quality of
life
it was however not in the final analysis
superior to a four-week application of a
topical medication but hey
cabbage leaves are safe can be used in
the longer term and so why not give them
a try
it also wouldn't hurt if you ate some as
well as cabbage may have internal
anti-inflammatory potential as well the
anti-inflammatory effects may explain
the health benefits of the cabbage
family vegetables not just potent
anti-inflammatory effects in petri
dishes
but
in people
10 days of broccoli consumption in
smokers
cut crp levels 40 percent
okay but what about for arthritis
in vitro sulforaphane the magic cabbage
chemical protects cartilage from
destruction suggesting that a high
cabbage or broccoli family vegetable
diet may be a useful measure either to
prevent or to slow the progression of
osteoarthritis
but even if sulforaphane can protect
cartilage cells in a petri dish how do
we even know that this compound makes it
into the joint when we eat it i mean no
one's ever done a study where you'd like
have people eat broccoli and stick a
needle in their knee joint to check
no one that is
until now
and sulforaphane was indeed detected in
the synovial fluid of 40 patients with
osteoarthritis following broccoli
consumption
followed by significant epigenetic
changes of gene expression within the
joint
the next step is to see if it can
actually improve
the disease
[Music]
so